[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Polluted water is desirable for aquatics.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "The act that students used to pass exam illegally is?",
        "correct": "Malpractice"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Nigeria lies at the extreme inner corner of the gulf of ?",
        "correct": "Guinea"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Nigeria was divided into protectorates, the protectorates were further divided into?",
        "correct": "Province"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "British divided Nigeria to protectorate, then to province, then to ?",
        "correct": "Units"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Nigeria has approximately 250 ethnic groups.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Newe was father of nationalism.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "First school in life is?",
        "correct": "Home"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "*ECOWAS* is only for English speaking countries.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Biotic and abiotic are living & dead.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "The Nigerian biggest hydropower is found in Niger state.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Art is not part of culture.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Islam has came to northern Nigeria through ..... traders.",
        "correct": "Arab"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "What is the oldest mean of communication? Town .....",
        "correct": "crier"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "African country is account for Berlin conference based on ..... revolution.",
        "correct": "Industrial"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Nigeria became first Republic in 1960-1963.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "J. H. Greenberg classified Nigerian language into 4.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Does our ethics allows us to wear European dressing?",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "The first population census in Nigeria is in 1963.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 20 ,
        "question": "For country to advance, its citizen has to improve political culture.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "Nigeria was colonized by British while Tunisia was colonized by French.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "..... means: _Nigerian National Democratic Party_",
        "correct": "NNDP"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "The first political party in Nigeria was?",
        "correct": "NNDP"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "Nigeria need a good ...... not a ruler",
        "correct": "Leader"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Berlin conference took place in 1884-.....",
        "correct": "1885"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "Tin is found in.",
        "correct": "Jos"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "Coal is found in Enugu and .....",
        "correct": "Anambara"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "Northern part of Nigeria is characterized by ..... savannah.",
        "correct": "Sahel"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "Hausa is a lingua franca in Enugu.",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "Lingua franca in Nigeria is?",
        "correct": "English"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "The major trade for the people in savannah zone is:",
        "correct": "d",
        "options": {
            "a": "Hunting",
            "b": "Farming",
            "c": "Trading",
            "d": "Farming and Trading"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "Karl max was born in?",
        "correct": "1818"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "Leather was started in ..... Land",
        "correct": "Hausa"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "Islam introduced into Nigeria in: ..... century",
        "correct": "11th"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "Jihad in sokoto was done in 19th century by:",
        "correct": "b",
        "options": {
            "a": "Sultan Muhammad Bello.",
            "b": "Sheikh Usman Bin Fodiyo.",
            "c": "Sheikh Inyaas.",
            "d": "Sheikh Dahiru Bauchi."
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "Environmental pollution leads to fire flame.",
        "correct": "a",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        }
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "Abolition of slave trade lead to the introduction of ..... trade",
        "correct": "Legitimate"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "The Berlin conference was conveyed by Otto von .....",
        "correct": "Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "..... is characterize by open land and tall grasses.",
        "correct": "Savannah"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "The sahel peoples depend on ..... as a source of economy.",
        "correct": "Farming"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "Discipline can be defined as? ..... and self control",
        "correct": "Orderliness"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "question": "Nigeria as entity became reality in 1914",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "question": "Niger Delter violence is as a result of",
        "options": {
            "a": "Oil spillage",
            "b": "Sociis economic cross",
            "c": "Selfishness"
        },
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "question": "Borno empire was divided into",
        "options": {
            "a": "Sections",
            "b": "Units",
            "c": "Provinces",
            "d": "Protectorates"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "question": "Constitutional monarchies are associated with?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Cephalopods",
            "b": "Centralized",
            "c": "Sedimentary",
            "d": "None of the above"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "question": "Colonial masters occupied peacefully in ..... land",
        "correct": "Yoruba"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "question": "Nigeria as ..... became reality in 1914",
        "correct": "entity"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "question": "Civilization aid in the spread of Islam in northern Nigeria.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "question": "The first Republic of Nigeria was from 1963-1966.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "question": "France practice the policy of ..... in all its colonies.",
        "correct": "Assimilation"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "question": "One of the factor of Berlin conference was: ..... revolution",
        "correct": "Industrial"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "question": "African were consulted by Berlin conference.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "question": "Berlin is the capital of",
        "correct": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "question": "African used the method of violence and ..... In gain of her independence",
        "correct": "Nonviolence"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "question": "Who assigned British to take influence over Nigeria? ..... conference.",
        "correct": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "question": "Nigerian geographical zone comprises how many states in each?",
        "correct": "6"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "question": "When did Nigeria became a republic state?",
        "correct": "1963"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "question": "What happened to British Parliament when Nigeria became republic? Their ..... was ceased.",
        "correct": "Power"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "question": "What happened to monarchical system when Nigeria became republic?",
        "correct": "Abolished"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "question": "Transparency, accountability & rule of law can only be relevant if there is good .....",
        "correct": "Government"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "question": "Nigeria located at: *_Latitude 4°E - 14°N & ..... 3°E - 15°N_*",
        "correct": "Longitude"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "question": "What is the 2 horses of court of arm representing? Pride and .....",
        "correct": "Dignity"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "question": "What is the super eagle representing?",
        "correct": "Strength"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "question": "To what extent can Nigeria be regarded as giant of Africa?",
        "correct": "Population"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "question": "Can history allow us to redefine ourselves as a Nation?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "question": "Is it true to say that exam malpractice can destroy relationship between the parent and institution?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "question": "The official language that serves as a mean of communication between different languages is called? Lingua .....",
        "correct": "Franca"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "question": "When did oil emerged in Nigeria? 1957/.....",
        "correct": "58"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "question": "When did oil revolution took place in Nigeria?",
        "correct": "1975"
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "question": "Why do we consider culture as survival strategy? It ..... man into particular environment.",
        "correct": "Fix"
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "question": "Is it reasonable to consider moral & sexual laxity as harmful to well-being of society?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "question": "Mai-tatsine crises was lead by Muhammad .....",
        "correct": "Marwa"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "question": "Is there any need for reorientation of our moral values?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "question": "Is it correct to say political plagiarism is designed to improve standard of government?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "question": "Moral obligation characters in the precolonial rule were well known & ensured in constitution",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "question": "Can we attribute the departure of cultural characteristics to autonomy village?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "question": "In Nigeria, we have dry season and .....",
        "options": {
            "a": "Rainy season",
            "b": "Raining season",
            "c": "Rain season"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "question": "Who is the founder of NNDP? Herbert .....",
        "correct": "Macauli"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "question": "The father of Nationalism was Herbert .....",
        "correct": "Macauli"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "question": "Nigeria is a country & west Africa is a subcontinent.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "question": "Lagos was destroyed in 1861 & reformed in .....",
        "correct": "1886"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "question": "Mode of pressing is not",
        "options": {
            "a": "Descent",
            "b": "Decent",
            "c": "Deset",
            "d": "Desent"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "question": "Fulani speak which of the following language in Nigeria?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Niger Congo",
            "b": "Afro Asiatic",
            "d": "Nilo Saharan"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "question": "Nigeria has about approximately 500 ethnic groups.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "question": "Presidential monarchies & villages found in:",
        "options": {
            "a": "Yoruba land",
            "b": "Igbo land",
            "c": "Hausa land",
            "d": "Tiv-Nupe"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "question": "Flowing of air in savannah can cause",
        "options": {
            "a": "Coldness",
            "b": "Dryness",
            "c": "Hotness",
            "d": "Freshness"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "question": "In savannah region, we experience ..... erosion.",
        "correct": "Soil"
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "question": "Nigeria derived it source from River Niger-Benue.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "question": "Land pollution is caused by",
        "correct": "Desertification"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "question": "Protectorate was formed in 1914.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "question": "Nigeria was separated into ..... in northern part",
        "correct": "Province"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "question": "Nigeria was separated into ..... in southern part",
        "correct": "Province"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "question": "Culture is universal.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "question": "Nigeria as a single entity became reality in",
        "correct": "1914"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "question": "H. O. David was the first father of nationalism.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "question": "Moral sexual relativity affect the behavior of a unit.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "question": "Islam came to Maiduguri through Arab traders.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "question": "Nigeria is the largest geographical zone in ..... Africa",
        "correct": "West"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "question": "The first governor general in Nigeria was: Sir Lord .....",
        "correct": "Lugard"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "question": "What is the status of political parties before 1951? ..... association.",
        "correct": "Cultural"
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "question": "All African languages are native to Africans except: English and .....",
        "correct": "Arabic"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "question": "African language is a classification of J. H. William.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "question": "Majority of Nigerian speak Niger .....",
        "correct": "Congo"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "question": "Categorisation of people is based on people's culture and",
        "options": {
            "a": "Trade relation",
            "b": "Social relation",
            "c": "Occupational ties"
        },
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "question": "Are Fulani citizens of world or northern Nigeria?",
        "correct": "World"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "question": "Nigeria has been facing a lot of crises, there is need to grab yard strategy. Must the president provide militaries with weapons?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "question": "Can we consider indigene and settler phenomenon as an inhabiting factor for conflict or ..... understanding each other?",
        "correct": "miss"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "question": "Major trade to citizenship in Nigeria Lies in the concept of foreigners.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "question": "When Nigeria became republic in 1963, British power was ceased and Monarchical system reinforced.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "question": "When military intervene in 1966, they begun politics. They lost their primary responsibilities to secondary responsibilities. Do we consider their participation of politics as *an aberration*?",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "question": "Nigerian military were created by British at independence.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "question": "When did Nigeria evolved/emerged as a modern nation? ..... century",
        "correct": "19th"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "question": "Man was created by God. However, man is a master of his own destiny.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "question": "Emanuel Kant said *\"man is a master of his own destiny\"* therefore, human creativity is disfunctional in every society.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "question": "The major languages spoken in Africa are Hausa and .....",
        "correct": "Swahili"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "question": "Niger-Congo family occupy the area of Senegal River valley in West Africa to the Shores of Indian Oceans",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "question": "Mutual suspicious among diverse ethnic groups is not only between majority and minority.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "question": "The highest duty of citizen is political",
        "options": {
            "a": "Participation",
            "b": "Act",
            "c": "Performance"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "question": "Negative conduct is an act that negates an acceptable form of",
        "options": {
            "a": "Believes",
            "b": "Believe",
            "c": "Belief",
            "d": "Behavior"
        },
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "question": "How many African countries became independence in 1960?",
        "correct": "17"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "question": "Nigeria celebrated century or hundred years of existence in:",
        "correct": "2014"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "question": "The total embedment of life process is:",
        "correct": "Culture"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "question": "Culture is an inevitable part of man.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "question": "Culture of a particular society is the totality of their life process.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "question": "Social institution help to regulate the behavior of people in society.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "question": "Behavior of people in society can be regulated by way of formal school only.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "question": "Political system can be effective through the process of check and balance",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "question": "J. H. Greenberg classified African languages into 4 classes called:",
        "correct": "Phyla"
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "question": "The history of poetry in Nigeria started since  BC.",
        "correct": "3000"
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a natural disaster?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Flooding & erosion",
            "b": "Flooding & draught",
            "c": "Flooding & desertification",
            "d": "Desert enrockment & oil spillage"
        },
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "question": "In Nigeria, the leadership in the subregion differs due to",
        "correct": "Environment"
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "question": "Most Igbo practice *crude* .....",
        "correct": "democracy"
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "question": "Before independence, Nigeria was using amalgamation Jack flag.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "question": "The following sources are causes of erosion except?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Wind",
            "b": "Rain",
            "c": "Heavy farming",
            "d": "Hunting"
        },
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "question": "Check and balance has to do with ..... establishment",
        "correct": "Military"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "question": "British colonial rule begun in",
        "correct": "1900"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "question": "Nigeria are black African most populated & influenced state.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "question": "Nigeria is giant of Africa.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "question": "There is no language from the Khoisan phylum in Nigeria.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "question": "Africa was divided during the time of ..... conference",
        "correct": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "question": "Nigeria has about 248 ethnic groups.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "question": "The principles & methods of distinguishing right from wrong & good from bad is ..... values",
        "correct": "Moral"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "question": "The major disaster in Nigeria are ..... and corruption.",
        "correct": "Bribery"
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "question": "Nigeria is more than 13 west African countries in terms of population.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "question": "NYSC was established in the year",
        "correct": "1976"
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "question": "Indigene-settler phenomenon in Nigeria was the creation of ..... nation.",
        "correct": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "question": "The most important physical feature in Nigeria is ..... Niger.",
        "correct": "River"
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "question": "Hausa are widely distributed throughout the states of Nigeria.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "question": "According to British, trade in palm oil, groundnut oil & cotton are referred to as legitimate trade.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "question": "Lagos was bombarded by the British in the year:",
        "correct": "1861"
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "question": "In recent years, Nigeria has witness violence crises between indigene and .....",
        "correct": "Settler"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "question": "Indigene is the native.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "question": "Pidgin English is a fusion of Hausa & Portuguese.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "question": "African civilization begins from which country ?",
        "correct": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "question": "Royal Niger company was established in",
        "correct": "1886"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "question": "Niger-Benue river divided Nigeria into ..... segments",
        "correct": "3"
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "question": "Select the odd",
        "options": {
            "a": "Sarki",
            "b": "Lamido",
            "c": "Shehu",
            "d": "Oba"
        },
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "question": "French is to Tanzania as British is to Nigeria.",
        "options": {
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False"
        },
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "question": "Select the odd",
        "options": {
            "a": "Perfume",
            "b": "Gunpowder",
            "c": "Book",
            "d": "Slave"
        },
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "question": "British used the method of ..... rule in northern part of Nigeria.",
        "correct": "Indirect"
    }
]